(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-25T16:42:59.526571",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ふたたび見る世界は
The world I see once again...
塵と残像 淡い影
...is a faint shadow of dust and remnants.
凛とした背中には
On your stoic back...
その全ての背負う覚悟がある
...there's a resolve to bear it all.
どうしたいの? どうして?
What do you want? Why?
孤独な旅 そう決めたはずだったのに
I was supposed to have chosen this solitary journey...
この手を離さないで
But don't let go of this hand.
君から伝わる思いから
From the feelings passed on by you,
心に眠る願いが目覚める
A wish awakens deep in my heart.
強い視線の彼方
Beyond that strong gaze,
迷いのない二人の姿が見える
I can see our unhesitating figures.
だから進むの 更なる時へ
So I'll move forward to a new time.
砕けていく風景に
In the crumbling scenery,
生きる事の奇跡を知る
I learn the miracle of living.
特別の意味求め
Seeking a special meaning,
彷徨い歩く道なき道を
Wandering on a path without light.
信じたいの 信じて 共に行く と
I want to believe, believe we'll go together.
そう決めて 欲しかったから
Because I wanted you to decide that.
瞳をそらさないで
Don't avert your eyes.
うまく言葉にできないけど
I can't put it into words properly, but
胸の深く君を求めている
Deep in my heart, I'm seeking you.
希望の遥か彼方
To the distant horizon of hope,
迷いのない二人の姿が見える
I can see our unhesitating figures.
だから進むの 次なる場所へ
So I'll move forward to the next place.
悔しさや悲しさが
The frustration and sadness...
今までそれ以上の喜びを教えてくれた
Have taught me the joy beyond all that until now.
そして、隣にいつも君という存在があるということも
And always by my side, that there's a presence called you,
感じるでしょう もう何も怖くない
You feel it too—you're not afraid of anything anymore.
届かせて この胸に
Reach out to this heart,
この手を握り締めて
clasping this hand tightly.
君にしか出せない力が
The power only you can unleash
夢を現実にかえてゆくから
will turn dreams into reality.
強い視線のあなた 迷い無いふたりの姿が
With your intense gaze, our unhesitating figures
見える だから包み込む優しさが
are visible. So when enveloping gentleness
重なる その時へ
overlaps into that moment...
はぁー！ はーい、ということで、えーみなさんこんぬい！
Haah! Hi everyone, so, um, hello everyone!
フロライブ3期生の不知火フレアです！
I'm Shiranui Flare from Hololive 3rd Gen!
本日は生誕祭2022私の誕生日のライブに来て下さり 皆さん本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you all so much for coming to my 2022 Birthday Live today!
本来私の誕生日4月なんですけど、まちょっといろんな自分のスケジュールの加えるとかもありまして、まちょっとね遅れまして6月にやらせていただくことになりました！
My birthday is actually in April, but due to various scheduling adjustments, it was delayed to June!
いや本当に待っててくれたエルフレンドたちも本当にね、お待たせしました！ありがとね！
Thank you so much to all the El-friends who waited for me! Thanks!
ま今日はね、たくさん盛り上がってもらえたら嬉しいなと思います
I hope you all get super hyped today!
みんなで楽しもーん！
Let's all have fun!
おれなんかでもちょっとステージが、もうちょっと…なんかないですか？
Wait, doesn't the stage need a bit more... of me in it?
なっ！スタッフ！おーほほほほ！
Wh-! Staff! Oh ho ho ho!
え、すごいモリ、モリになってめっちゃモリ！
Whoa, it's so forest-y and super lush!
え、なんかエルフレンドも、もしかしてこれなに、立體的？
Wait, are the El-friends 3D too?
立体じゃね？え、すごくない？動いてる、ちょっと動いて。え、まばたきしてる！かわいい！
They are 3D, right? Isn't that amazing? They're moving! They're blinking! So cute!
え、そんな君たちは、INE、JPE、だ、オーソドックスなのもいるけど、君たちは何してくれる係今日？
So you guys, INEs, JPEs, there are orthodox ones too, what are you in charge of doing today?
え、太鼓？ え、かわいい！
Huh, drums? Aww, cute!
え、INE、INE君は？
What about INE-kun?
わ、かわいい！マラカス！しゃんしゃんしゃん…
Oh, cute, maracas! Shake shake shake...
えじゃあ、普通のオーソドックス君は？
And what about the regular orthodox one?
あ、タンバリン！かわいいね！
Ah, a tambourine! How cute!
ていうことて今日はですね、エルフレンドたちと一緒にこのライブを盛り上げていきますので、みんなもたくさん楽しんでください！では、いってみましょー！
So today, together with the El-friends, we're gonna hype up this live, so everyone please enjoy yourselves! Now, let's go!
この度この太陽系に 新たに惑星を作る神様です
We are gods creating a new planet in this solar system.
会議で決まった予算は 日本円にして1000京円
The budget decided in meeting is 10,000 quadrillion yen.
潤沢とは決して言えませんが そこは私の腕の見せ所
We certainly can't call it lavish, but that's where I show my skills.
神々の節約テクを駆使して 体裁だけは保ってみましょう
By making full use of gods' frugal tech, let's keep up appearances.
低予算で作った生き物に 人間と名付けてみました
To the creatures made on a low budget, we named them humans.
誤動作だらけの陳腐なオツム 足りないパーツは7ダース
Trite brains full of malfunctions, missing 7 dozen parts.
彼らはなかなか厄介なハッシュド精神力を お持ちで
They possess quite troublesome hashed willpower,
いつも困ったことがあるとすぐ私に祈るのです
so whenever they have trouble, they immediately pray to me.
低予算で作った生き物に
To the creatures made on a low budget,
人間と名付けてみました 誤動作だらけの陳腐なおツム
we named them humans. Trite brains full of malfunctions,
足りないパーツは7ダース
missing 7 dozen parts.
彼らはなかなか厄介なハッシュド精神力をお持ちで
They possess quite troublesome hashed willpower,
いつも困ったことがあるとすぐ私に祈るのです
so whenever they have trouble, they pray to me immediately!
祈りはフリーダイヤルみたいに使な!
Don't use prayer like a toll-free number!
費用はこっちで負担してるんだぞ!
We're covering expenses here!
そんなところにお金がかかると オゾン層を維持するお金を削っちゃうぞ
If you spend money there, we'll cut ozone maintenance funds!
お前の半熟脳みそと天界を 有線LANでつないでやろうか!
Shall I connect your half-baked brains and heaven via wired LAN?!
人間と名付けた生き物は 足りないオツムで考える
Creatures named humans think with their lacking brains.
彼らは好奇心が旺盛で この星の秘密を知りたがる
They are full of curiosity and want to know the secrets of this star.
脱脂綿詰めただけの地殻 エアコン切れていただけの氷河期
Crusts with absorbent cotton, ice ages with the AC off.
恐竜の化石は趣味のプラモ どうか気づかないで!
Dinosaur fossils are hobby plastic models, please don't notice!
ブレーカー落ちている間にマンモス滅んだ
Mammoths went extinct while the breaker was tripped.
これぞオール電化惑星のリスク
Behold the risk of an all-electric planet!
この度この太陽系に
This time, in this solar system,
新たに惑星をつくる神様なです
I am the god creating a new planet.
会議で決まった予算は
The budget decided in the meeting
日本円にして千兆円
in Japanese yen is 1 quadrillion yen.
順調とは決して言えませんが
I certainly wouldn't call it going smoothly,
そこは私の腕の見所
that's where I get to show my true skills.
神々の節約テクを駆使して
Making full use of the gods' frugality techniques,
体裁だけは見せてみましょう
let's at least keep up appearances.
てきとうに作った生き物に
To the creatures I hastily created
人間と名づけてみました
I gave the name of humans.
誤作動だらけのちんぴな御頭
A simpleton head full of malfunctions,
足りないパーツは七日アス
missing parts delivered in seven days.
彼らはなかなかなかなか厄介な発想精神力をお持ちで
They are quite, quite troublesome, with resourceful minds,
いつも困ったことがあるとすぐに私に祈るのです
whenever they are in trouble, they immediately pray to me.
祈りをフリーダイヤルみたいにつかうな！
Don't use prayers like a toll-free number!
費用はこっちで負担してるんだぞ！
We're the ones covering the costs here!
そんなところにお金がかかると
If costs pile up in places like that,
オゾン層を維持するお金を削っちゃうぞ
we'll end up cutting the ozone layer budget!
予算があれば
If we had a budget,
地磁気はまっすぐにできたし
we could have made the geomagnetism straight,
完璧な生き物にもできたんだ
and even created perfect living beings.
でも偶然
But by chance,
地磁気の傾きは四季を生んで
the tilt of the geomagnetism created the four seasons,
不完全な心は愛を生んだ
and an imperfect heart created love.
案がいい星になった
It turned out to be a pretty good planet.
でももう懲りこんくそ星すぐ売るわ
Still, I've had enough, I'm selling this damn planet!
そのお金で
With that money,
天国の個室買う！
I'll buy a private room in heaven!
あとはせいぜいうまく歩めよ
As for the rest, you better walk well on your own,
私なしじゃすぐ死ぬだろうけど！
even though you'll probably die without me!
せっかくだし最後に
Since it's the final moment,
有給でもとって温泉に行くかあ
maybe I'll take paid leave and go to a hot spring!
あー！よかったねえ！
Ah, that was so good!
いい曲だった！
It was such a good song!
ご飯美味しかった！
The food was delicious!
ねえ、最後だったね！
Right, that was the ending!
いや、なんかねねちとはさ、ご飯とかウラではね、結構行ったりとかさ、そう、しているんだけどさ
Well, Nenechi and I go out to eat behind the scenes quite a bit, yeah, we do that...
ね、温泉も初めてだね、じゃなくって...ま、それはおいといて、
Right, and it's our first time at a hot spring... wait, no... Well, putting that aside,
今日ね、来てくれてどうもありがとうございました！
thank you so much for coming today!
いやこちらこそ！誕生日おめでとう！ありがとう！
No, thank you! Happy birthday! Thank you!
いやなんかさ、ねねちとはさ、こうコラボとかさ、実は2人でとかはないじゃない？
You know, Nenechi and I, we don't really do collabs just the two of us, right?
あ、確かに確かに！
Oh, true, true!
そう、なんかゴールデンウィークとかにもさ、一緒にゲーム盛り上がったりとかね
Yeah, like during Golden Week we got excited playing games together,
頑張ったりとかね、したけどさ、ね、だから2人でなんかすくるっていうのずっと、
and worked hard on things... so I've actually always wanted to try doing something together.
え、えー！なにそれ！嬉しいんだけど！
Eh, ehh! What is that?! I'm so happy!
ねねち！嬉しい嬉しい！
Nenechi! Yay, yay!
でさ、でもねねちってさ、結構なんか高いのとかも出るってさ、あの聞いたからさ
And you know, Nenechi, I heard that you can hit really high notes sometimes,
で、こえたまもさ、歌うときとかもさ、めちゃめちゃ高いのとか出るからさ、あの、この歌を
and you also hit super high notes when singing, so I thought, I've actually always wanted to sing this song...
あの、実はいつか歌いたいと思ってたんだけど、歌えるのもねねちしかいないんじゃないかと思って
And I figured Nenechi would be the only one who could sing it, so...
ちょっとさ、ねねちとは、普通の曲じゃなくて、なんかちょっと面白い、かつ、なんかしたい曲
And you know, with Nenechi, not just a normal song, but something a bit interesting and fun,
歌いたいなと思ってて、ねねちにぴったりじゃんって思ってたんだよね。
I wanted to sing, and I thought it would be a perfect fit for Nenechi!
いやねねね、この曲、あの、フータに教えてもらって初めて、あの、覚えたんだけど、
Nene, I actually learned this song for the first time after Futa-chan taught it to me,
いや本当なんか不思議な曲だし、でも楽しくて、でも高いわ！
and it's such a mysterious song, but fun, and so high!
いやでもね、本当にありがとう！すごいいいかったよ！
Well, really thank you so much, it was amazing!
いや、ねねたち声の相性めちゃめちゃ良くない？ある！それは本当そう。
Nene, aren't our voices a great match? Yes! That's so true.
また一緒に歌おうよ！ねえ、歌いたい歌いたい！
Let's sing together again! Yeah, I want to sing!
ね、今めちゃめちゃ疲れてると思うけど、ねねちゃんさ、ちょっと頑張ってからね。
You must be super tired right now, but you worked hard.
いや本当にありがとう！リハとかもね、いやほんと歌だけとは言わずね、あのゲームもね、よろしくおねがいしますわ！
Thank you so much! Rehearsals too... not just singing, but games too, please take care of me!
じゃあ写真撮ろう、写真！
Let's take a photo, a photo!
あ、撮る撮る撮る撮る！イェーイ！ピース！ハッピーバー、ハッピーバー！ハッピー！イェーイ！ありがとう！ありがとう！
Ah, take it! Yay! Peace! Happy b-day, happy b-day! Happy! Yay! Thank you! Thank you!
ちょっとまださ、あの
Hey, we still have...
人間、あの地球のさ、あの、お金残ってるからさ、
some human, Earth money left over,
もう一トプール行かない？
so shouldn't we go to the pool again?
あ、行こ行こ行こよ！
Ah, let's go, let's go!
別府とか海行こ！
Let's go to Beppu or the ocean!
えー！
Eh?!
イエーイ！
Yay!
レッツゴーレッツゴーレッツゴー！
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
劣等上等 BRING IT ON
Bottom to top, bring it on
列島上々 不眠日日本
Jumpin' J-Pan, number one
子供騙しのマセマティカ
I'm over all this stupid Mathematica
ご立派 警鐘 気取りで
Putting on a show but I'm over it now
高みの見物ばかりじゃつまんないね
Riding upon a horse up high, I wanna get down
ほらもっと 間違って上等
Again they don't see, that I'm really not king
退屈に手をかけて
And every day repeating all the same
ママ、やっぱりあたしは
Mama, I dunno what to do,
こんなところじゃ終われない
I couldn't stop it tonight
ぬるくて 気 が触れそう
And maybe I'm going crazy,
ごっこ遊びも芝居もさようなら
living my life in a fantasy
ずっとこのままだなんてさ
No more playing around, say goodbye,
いらないよ
I don't need it, no
ダッダッダ あたし大人になる
Da da da, I'm growing up and out
酸いも甘いも噛み分けて今
Tasting all of the sweet and sour things
パッパッパ 変わる時代
Pa pa pa, I'm changing up, believe
悪いことばかりじゃないでしょう
In every word that I say
過去も、罪も、罰も、すべて
All the past, all the sin, all the pain
素手で、愛で、生き抜いてやり返すわ
Make it through with my hands and love
yeah, 挑戦 あたし達は no doubt
Yeah, we out, making you crazy no doubt
緑のアイツにばっか構ってんね
Don't be talkin' 'bout that green ho with no flow again
さあ burn up いつになったら貰える合格
So burn up as I pass in the rearview, so what?
赤ペンいれてよ どこがダメなんですか
Need a pen? Any red? Bet I get a hundred and ten like I said
酒女金ドラッグ チルって aiight...
Girls, liquor, money, and drugs, you know they gonna say yes
冗談じゃんブラックジョーク
Chill out, it's aight, just makin' mean jokes
中指立てたくなるような事情
If I gotta raise a middle finger up again
ありすぎて指が足りねえから hands up and what's up
Gonna throw both my hands up, hey what's up, ya jerk?
最低? もともとだろ bring it on
Gimme what you got now, bring it on
「まあまあ」なんかいらない
I'm done being a no one
欲しがります死ぬまでは
Before I die, I'm gonna see something through
伸びた背中 育った街に投げキス
Standing tall, the place I grew up, I blow a kiss
見場はこっちから 覚悟しときよ
Cuz soon they'll see a me that they never knew!
ダッダッダ ぼくら大人になる
So are you ready for the...
カウンター狙い 最低な日々に
Counting down on the days, that I grew to really hate
喃々とかます一撃
Ta ta ta attack 'em all, turn down
誰も読めない先まであいこでしょ
They couldn't read at all, it's a draw, die another day
バグも、ロスも、ずれも、すべて
All the bugs, all the loss, all the gaps and the cost
素手で、生きて! 生き抜いて覆すの
We will live on our own, living on in spite of all that we know
くらないことばかりが譲れない
Na na na now I'll never lose
わかるか あたしの美学
Not to stupid things I couldn't choose
この馬鹿正直な拳ひとつが
But do you see the beauty that I need?
(一途なんです) 切り札 (愚直なんです)
With an honest fist for justice, stupid though it may seem
がなる劣等 一抜けろさらば!
Ace up my sleeve, weakly I shout above, my last goodbye!
ダッダッダ あたし大人になる
Da da da, I'm growing up and out into the world
酸いも甘いも噛み分けて今
Tasting all of the sweet, maybe even sour things
燦々 交わるミライ
Pa pa pa, I'm changing up, believe
もう子供じゃないのわかるでしょう
In every word that I say cuz it's coming from me
時代 機会 待ってくれない
Time will pass, like this chance, they don't wait, better act
素手で、捨て身で、生き抜いて上等だわ
On my own, bet my life, bring it on, I know that I'll survive
愛ある時代
Era of love alive
それでは皆様お先に bye, guys!
Well ladies and gentlemen, we'll see y'all later!
ダッダッダ あたし大人になる
Da da da, I'm growing up and aiming at the world
大人に鳴る風邪も甘いも
Counting down on the days, that I grew to really hate
わかるか あたしの美学
They couldn't read at all, it's a draw, die another day
この馬鹿正直な拳ひとつが
All the bugs, all the loss, all the gaps and the cost
一途なんだって 切り札
We will live on our own living on in spite of all that we know
愚直なんですがなるルレント
Na na na now I'll never lose
一抜けろさらば
Not to stupid things I couldn't choose
ダッダッダ あたし大人になる
Da da da, I'm growing up and out into the world
酸いも甘いも噛み分けて今
Tasting all of the sweet, maybe even sour things
ダッダッダ あたし大人になる
Da da da, I'm growing up and out into the world
酸いも甘いも噛み分けて今
Tasting all of the sweet, maybe even sour things
パッパッパ 変わる時代
Pa pa pa, I'm changing up, believe
さぁ交わるミライも過去もじゃないのわかるでしょ
In every word that I say cuz it's coming from me
時代機械待ってくれない
Time will pass, like this chance, they don't wait, better act
素手で、せみで、生き抜いて上等だわ
On my own, bet my life, bring it on, I know that I'll survive
愛ある時代
Era of love alive
それでは皆様お先に bye, guys!
Well ladies and gentlemen, we'll see y'all later!
フローラ
Flora...
爆上がりました
busted out!
ああ、上げた手を下げちゃったよ！
Ah, I put down the hand I raised!
上げた手でじゃんけんをしちゃったよ！
I ended up playing rock-paper-scissors with the raised hand!
今さ、何だった？
Wait, what was that just now?
え、グーだよ。
Uh, it was rock.
え、じゃあ勝ったわ。
Ah, then I won.
なんねえ！うそん！
No way! You liar!
今パーだったもん。じゃんけんしてた？
It was paper just now. / Were you doing rock-paper-scissors?
え、じゃあせっかくだからじゃんけんしとく？
Well, since we have the chance, want to do rock-paper-scissors?
最初のグー、すのまき、すのまき、すのまき、すのまき、すのまき、すのまき、すのまき
First is rock, Sunomaki, Sunomaki...
じゃんけん、ポン！
Rock-paper-scissors, shoot!
あいこでしょ！
Aiko desho!
いや、今日はありがとうね、来てくれて。
Man, thank you so much for coming today.
こちらこそ、こんなね、お誕生日やん！
Likewise, for such a... birthday!
そうなんだよ。
That's right.
おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
呼んでくれて嬉しいじゃん。
I'm so glad you invited me.
いやなんか前にさ
Yeah, like before...
あの私たち二人で歌うっていうのは初めてだったのその時。
When we did that live before, it was the first time the two of us sang together.
そうだね。
That's right.
そこで歌ったのがすごい良かったなと思って、相性めっちゃええやんと思って。
And singing together there was so great, I thought our chemistry was amazing.
また歌いたいなと思って。
So I wanted us to sing together again.
その時もね、この曲も、ま候補に上がって、そうそうそうそうそう。
Right. At that time too, this song was also one of the candidates, yeah, yeah, yeah.
ね、なんか今回、あの私に声かけさせてもらう時に、やっぱどうしてもこの曲やっぱ候補からちょっと外せないよと思って。
Right, and when I reached out to ask you this time, I felt like I just couldn't leave this song off the list.
あ、これちょっとやってみませんか？って
So I asked, "Would you like to try doing this?"
ね！やってみましょうや！って。
Right! Let's do it!
私めがね、やろうって言ってくれて。でめっっちゃよかったよね！
Yeah. Watame said let's do it. And it was really great, right!
めっちゃよかった、めっちゃ高かったけどね。
It was really great, though it was super high-pitched.
それな。えでなんか最後とかさ、あの、おくしたと、うくえって感じ、ちょうどいい感じでマッチしてたと思わんか？
Totally. And at the end, don't you think it matched just right?
思わんか？みんなも思わんか？えー！
Don't you think? Doesn't everyone think so too? Yay!
えー！
Yay!
最後みんなと一緒にさ、撮って終わろう。オッケー！イェーイ！
Finally, let's take a photo with everyone and wrap up. Okay! Yay!
イェーイ！イェーイ！イェーイ！イェーイ！
Yay! Yay! Yay! Yay!
ナイトフィーバー！フー！フー！フー！フー！
Night Fever! Woo! Woo! Woo! Woo!
はい、ということでね、今日はありがとうございました！ありがとうございました！
Yes, so thank you very much for today! Thank you so much!
また呼ぶからね！だしいっぱい呼ぶ！またコラボもしようね！
I'll invite you again! I'll invite you lots of times! Let's collab again too!
しようしよう！ありがとね！ありがとね！ありがとね！
Let's, let's! Thank you! Thank you! Thank you!
バイバイ、ありがとね！ありがとね！バイバイ！
Bye-bye, thank you! Thank you! Bye-bye!
うちの家系、バンバンバン
Our family line, bang, bang, bang!
まずは生きるか死ぬか突き詰め命ぜばそれだけ、あとはどうにかなっちゃうもんだって
First off, if you push yourself to live or die, that's all there is to it!
確かに、よく聞け、ここじゃ泣き言とはいらねえぜ
True enough, listen well, no whining is needed here!
相性どうしよう、断捨離の間隔で
Compatibility? What should we do? With the mindset of spring-cleaning,
脳をアワワ、ザ・クレイジー、だいぶいい感じ、体に叩き込め
wash your brain, the crazy, quite a good feel, hammer it into your body!
スタイル、トゥー・ザ・クレイジー、なで切るのは百万年、はい！
Style, to the crazy, slashing away takes a million years, yes!
いつでもそう、いつでもそう立ちふさがるのは覚悟だけ、弱い自分だって
Always so, what stands in your way is only resolve, even your weak self!
つまりライフ、古い情操、先にしてネガティブ、徹底的に
In short, life, old sentimentality, put negativity first, thoroughly
煮詰め、もうちょっと優しくなれないハートで、引き金を引きまくれ
stew it, with a heart that can't be a little kinder, pull the trigger!
岩は完全無欠、硬く刈り取れ
The boulder is flawless and hard, reap it away!
濁素で錆びた価値観じゃ、感覚舐まる、すぐにハイ・ジョーセーヨ
With a rusted value system, your senses grow dull, raise your emotions!
天上、天界われら特攻、右向け左、イェッサー！左向け左、イェッサー！
Heaven, heavenly realm, we are a special attack force! Right face, left!
そのまますすめ、イェッサー！絶対絶命、助けて！
Keep moving straight ahead! Yes, sir! Desperate situation, help me!
超脳舞台とはまずは先客に呼ぶがじょーほっししりほんだって
A super brain stage is first called by early guests wanting information!
必要な損失、それは最高級のIQ、解毒洗浄、確実に錯乱のロマンで
Necessary loss, top-tier IQ, detoxification, romance of delirium!
ウォオオ、ザ・クレイジー、だいぶいい感じ、真実をマブリーヌで
Woah, the crazy, quite a good feel, wrap the truth in "mabloune"!
ウォオオ、ザ・クレイジー、踊らせろ、おどらせてやれよ
Woah, the crazy, make them dance, let them dance!
いつでもそう、いつでもそう感じることわからせない、しかしそれがショック！
Always so, not letting you feel what you feel, but that's a shock!
常にインテリジェンス、磨いて世界を、決定的に脅かす
Constantly polish your intelligence, threatening the world decisively!
もしチグハグな学乱、どこかで神さえ青ざめるくらい、岩は完全無欠、硬く刈り取れ
If disjointed chaos makes gods pale, the boulder is flawless, reap it!
ウォオオ、ザ・クレイジー、にご、そで錆びた価値観じゃ感覚舐まる
With rusted values, senses grow dull!
白兵戦、追撃戦、地上戦、陸上戦、空中戦、情報戦、制空権、経済戦、サイバー戦
Hand-to-hand, pursuit, ground, land, air, intelligence, economic, cyber!
つまりライフ、古い情操、先にしてネガティブ、徹底的に
In short, life, old sentimentality, put negativity first, thoroughly
煮詰め、もうちょっと優しくなれないハートで、引き金を引きまくれ
stew it, with a heart that can't be a little kinder, pull the trigger!
岩は完全無欠、硬く刈り取れ
The boulder is flawless and hard, reap it away!
濁素で錆びた価値観じゃ、感覚なまる、すぐにハイ・ジョーセーヨ
With a rusted value system, your senses grow dull, raise your emotions!
完全無欠、血の気の多さはその手に、圧倒的な勝利を
Flawless, the bloodthirst in your hands brings overwhelming victory!
もしチグハグな学乱、どこかで神さえ青ざめるくらい、岩は完全無欠、限界少女になるまで
If chaos makes gods pale, the boulder is flawless, until you break limits!
尊厳を無力化して任務にしたがえ
Neutralize your dignity and obey your mission!
天上、天界われら特攻、右向け左、左向け左、そのまますすめ天上、天界われら特攻
Heaven, heavenly realm, we are a special attack force! Right face, left!
いやなんかさ、叶たん叶った！
Hey, like, Kanata-tan, it came true!
いやてんぱい
No, I'm panicking!
いや今日来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you so much for coming today!
いや本当！
Yeah, really!
いやこちらこそお誕生日おめでとうございます！
No, thank you so much, and Happy Birthday!
ありがとう！お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Thank you! Happy Birthday!
いやなんかさ、叶たんどうそう？
Hey, like, Kanata-tan, how was it?
あのなんか結構、今年とか去年の終わりぐらいから、
Well, like, from around this year or late last year, quite a lot...
コラボとかあの出演させていただいたりとかね。
like collaborations and appearing on shows.
あの知床でちょっと仲良くなってきたなと思って
I felt like we've gotten quite close since Shiretoko,
なのでなんか歌とかも歌いたいなと思って、
so I thought I'd like to sing together too,
いや本当！ね！
Yeah, really! Right!
そうこの曲とかも、なんかかっこいいところ、あの白平各劇戦闘歴記録女子とか
Yeah, and this song too, the cool parts like Shiranui's combat records of female warriors,
あそこ絶対叶たんに歌ってもらったら、かっこいいなと思って、
I thought it would be so cool if Kanata-tan sang that part,
いやもうめちゃソロパート偏ってて、いやもうそんな、いいのかな、こんなにいっぱいうたってって思ったんですけど、
and my solo parts were so biased, I thought, is it really okay to sing this much? But,
めちゃめちゃめちゃめちゃかっこよかった！最初練習した時マジで言えなくて、
it was so, so cool! When I practiced at first, I really couldn't say it,
めっちゃ練習しました！
I practiced so much!
いやほんとにありがとう！いやこちらこそね、誘っていただいて本当に嬉しかったです。ありがとうございます！
No, really, thank you! No, I'm the one who should thank you, I was so happy you invited me. Thank you so much!
ありがとう！次話あの、カナリアで歌いたいね。
Thank you! Next time, um, I want to sing 'Canaria' together.
ね、ちょっと小夜をね、このね、小夜を呼ばなきゃ
Right, we gotta invite Sayo for that too,
呼んでカナリアでも歌、歌いますよね。
and sing 'Canaria' together too.
ね、えちょっとさ、記念撮影もしよう。
Right? Um, let's also take a commemorative photo.
撮って、ねえ、みんなも一緒に
Take it, and everyone together too,
エルフラとヘイミンを入れて
including Elf-la and Heimin,
あ、そうそう、みんな
Ah, right, right, everyone,
よし、いいえーい！
Alright, Yay!
ここにね次はカナリアで、小夜も入れて、いやマジで小夜で、いえーい！いなきゃいけないけど、今度ここに入るからな。
Next time with Canaria, including Sayo, no really with Sayo, Yay! She has to be here, but she'll be in here next time.
はい、ということでね、叶たん本当にありがとう。今度はまたコラボも一緒にしようね、
Alright, so Kanata-tan, thank you so much. Let's do another collab together again,
てか焼き肉行かなきゃ！焼肉行きましょうね。
or rather we gotta go to yakiniku! Let's go to yakiniku.
まず焼き肉の
First, for the yakiniku,
奢らせていただきます。
I'll treat you.
ありがとう！本当にありがとうございます。ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you so much. Thank you!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
涙の向こうに かかる虹を
Beyond the tears, a rainbow that appears,
いつかは超えて行ける
We will surely cross over someday,
信じて My Friend
Believe it, My Friend.
時は 戸惑うことなく寄せる
Time gathers without hesitation,
波のようだね 泳ぎ疲れ
Like the waves, tired of swimming,
いつしか ながされてそうになっていたよ
Before I knew it, I was swept away...
空は あれからいくつも 季節 運んで
The sky has carried many seasons since then,
君の 声を こんなに小さく変えていた
Making your voice sound so small.
なんて 何かを掴んだ 指の隙間
What is it? Between fingers that tried to grasp something,
キラキラ 輝いて こぼれたものは何？
What was it that glittered and spilled out?
うまくできるほど 苦しくなる
The better I try to do things, the more painful it gets.
誰よりも君は ほら 気づいている
More than anyone else, look, you've noticed,
気づいている そして いつでも平気な
You've noticed, and you always put on a brave
顔を するたび 塞ぐ耳で 傷んだ
face, blocking your ears, hurting...
涙を拭いてたんだ 僕も
I was wiping away my tears too,
涙で滲んだ ビルの上に
on top of the buildings blurred by tears.
見上げる憧れは
The longing I look up to
確かにここにある
is definitely right here.
あの日の胸にかけた虹を
The rainbow cast upon my chest that day,
追いかけ走り出そう
let's run in pursuit of it!
笑って My Friend
Smile, my friend.
長い夜が止むその時
When the endless night finally stops,
光をください
please give me light.
迷わずに二度と離さないよ
I'll never hesitate or let go again.
涙で滲んだ ビルの上に
On top of the buildings blurred by tears,
見上げる憧れは
the longing I look up to
確かにここにある
is definitely right here.
あの日の胸にかけた虹を
The rainbow cast upon my chest that day,
追いかけ走り出そう
let's run in pursuit of it!
笑って My Friend 微かでいいんだ
Smile, my friend, even a faint one is fine.
明日の風に吹かれて僕たちは
Blowing in tomorrow's wind, we
生きていけるはずさ
are bound to keep living on.
涙の向こうにかかる虹を
The rainbow spanning across the tears—
いつかは超えてゆこう
someday we'll overcome it and go on!
信じて My Friend
Believe, my friend.
笑って My Friend
Smile, my friend.
愛しくて 切なくて 抱きしめたくて
So dear, so painful, I want to hold you tight,
この胸高鳴るよ だって、大好きだから。
my heart beats fast because I love you so much!
照りつける太陽 キラリはじめて
The scorching sun begins to sparkle,
キミを夏色に染めた Ah 時が止まる
dyeing you in summer colors. Ah, time stands still.
今はまだキッカケつかめなくて
I still can't find the right chance yet,
全力疾走 キミとなり 自転車で追い越してくよ
running at full speed beside you on my bike.
失敗して またへこんじゃっても
Even if I fail and get down again,
その笑顔見たいから 頑張ってみるよ
I want to see your smile, so I'll try my best.
ありったけの「好き」をキミに伝えたくて
I want to tell you all my feelings of love,
この夏駆け抜ける 想いはもう止められないから
dashing through this summer; I can't stop now.
青空走る 飛行機雲に乗って
Riding the contrail across the blue sky,
キミに近づきたい だって、大好きだから。
I want to get closer because I love you so much!
ちょっと待ってよ いきなりすぎない？
Wait a second, isn't this too sudden?!
だいたい何でこうなるわけなの？
Why does it always end up like this?!
会う度いつも喧嘩喧嘩
Every time we meet, we're always fighting!
でも本当は好きとかそういうんじゃなくて！
It's not like I actually like you or anything!
わかんない気にしすぎてるかも
I don't know, maybe I'm overthinking it.
愛しくて 切なくて 抱きしめたくて
So dear, so painful, I want to hold you tight,
この胸高鳴るよ だって、大好きだから！
this heart beats fast because I love you so much!
キミともっと一緒にいたい Yeah Wow
I want to be with you even more, yeah, wow!
ボクをもっと知ってほしい Yeah Wow
I want you to know me better, yeah, wow!
Happy Happy Birthday!
訳分かんない 訳分かんない
I don't get it at all, I don't get it at all!
自分の この気持ち
This feeling of my own
理解 不能だよ
Is completely incomprehensible!
恋しちゃこいしちゃ恋しちゃペコラ
Falling in love, falling in love with Pekora!
ねぇ 誰かを教えて
Hey, tell me who it is.
ここはどこ マンガのなか
Where is this? Inside a manga?
教科書どこにも載ってないし
It's not in any textbook either!
こんな気持ちは初めてだから
Because a feeling like this is a first for me.
ああ そういえば いつか私が 迷い込んだ時
Ah, come to think of it, when I wandered in sometime...
大丈夫 大丈夫 なんとかなるよって
"It'll be alright, it'll somehow work out," they said,
大きく 笑ってくれた
And smiled so broadly at me.
訳分かんない 訳分かんない
I don't get it at all, I don't get it at all!
ねぇ 告白するなんて
To actually confess, you know...
突然すぎるよ
It's way too sudden!
なんでどうして 私の胸
Why, how come, my chest
破裂しそうなの
Feels like it's going to burst!
目があうの目が合うの目が合うとドキッちゃう
When our eyes meet, my heart goes doki!
白桃じゃ 笑わないでパピラ
It's white peach! Don't laugh, Papira.
チョキンじゃ 白桃じゃ パピラピラピラパピラ
Chokin ja, hakutō ja, Papira-pira-pira-Papira!
最後のサプライズと…
With the final surprise...
いや、近、近かったね。近すぎて
Man, that was close, so close. Too close!
囁いちゃった、囁いちゃった
I whispered, I whispered!
いや、最後あれ？風邪で囁いてもらえるかと思ってたけど
Wait, at the end? I thought you'd whisper in the wind, but...
いやもう、緊張でどうしていいか分かんないですけど、もう、いいじゃいいじゃ、おー！
Man, I was so nervous I didn't know what to do, but whatever, oh!
いやそれよりもフレア、お誕生日おめでぴこー！
More importantly Flare, happy birthday, Piko!
ありがとうございます、本当に！
Thank you so much, really!
いや、一緒に歌えてすっごい嬉しかったの、ペコラ。二人ってなかなかさ、なくね？
I was so happy to sing together with you, Pekora. We rarely get to do this, right?
いや、そうなだよね。今回私、本当に初めて、てかこの衣装で
Yeah, that's right. This time, for me, it's truly the first time, I mean in this outfit
あの、一緒にちゃんと歌うの初めてじゃない？
Um, isn't this our first time properly singing together?
いや、しかもさ、ペコラとさ、フレアの、一緒の衣装ってシナジーあるよね？
And plus, Pekora and Flare's matching outfits have synergy, right?
そうなんだよね。青とさ、白って感じでね。
That's right. With blue and white, you know.
いい感じ、ペコラ？えへへ
Good vibe, Pekora? Ehehe
いや、もう、激しすぎてさ、全然感想中にさ、喋る余裕なかったんだけどさ
Man, it was so intense that I had no room to talk during the chorus at all, but
そう、逆逆に、もっともっと、あの
Yeah, conversely, even more, um
みんなと一緒にしさ、その、動きに集中しすぎて声が…
With everyone, like, concentrating too much on the movement, my voice...
出せるかな？イェーイ！
Can I get it out? Yay!
いや本当に本当に今日来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you so much for coming today!
ありがとうぺこー！
Thank you, Peko!
いやなんかさ、一緒にさ、歌いたかったんだけど、その、よいこりさんの曲を
I wanted to sing together with you, like, Yoikori-san's song, and
そのペコラと一緒に歌ったら絶対可愛いんじゃないかって思ってたの！
I thought that if I sang it together with Pekora, it would be super cute!
いや、本当ぺこりすこですけど
Truly Peko-risuko, but
すっごいさ、可愛いって曲だよね、これね。うん！
It's such a cute song, isn't it? Yeah!
一緒に歌えてよかった！
I'm so glad we could sing it together!
いや、こちらこそありがとうペコだよ！
Well, thank you too, Peko!
まだまだあるもんね、もう。そうなんだよ、まだまだね、ちょっとコラボとかもね、あったり
There's still more, right? Yeah, there's still some collabs and stuff
私の曲とかもあったりするので、がんばってペコな、ペコラを見守っててね！
and my songs too, so do your best and watch over Peko, watch over Pekora!
ありがとうね、ずっちゃん！
Thank you, Zucchan!
がんばってね、フレア、頑張ってね！
Do your best, Flare, do your best!
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!
どんなに どんなに 手を取り合っていても
No matter how, no matter how much we hold hands together,
最後から 最後まで 始まりはない
From beginning to end, there is no true start.
繊細で 臆病な やわらかな心 壊さないよう 守ろう
A delicate, timid, and tender heart— let's protect it so it won't break.
希望の中で 迷子の欠片 もうあの日と違っても 受け入れるよ
A lost fragment amidst hope, even if it's different from that day, I'll accept it.
どうしても… 欲しくて あげたくなくて
Why... I want it, yet I don't want to give it away.
いつだって いつだって 優しくなれないの
Always, always, I cannot be kind.
理解して 向き合った 嘘つきな世界
Understanding and facing this deceitful world,
怯えてた 今までの 後悔 私と消えて
All the regrets I've been afraid of up until now—disappear with me.
本当なんてなくてって 笑おう
Even if there's no such thing as truth, let's smile.
怖がってた 今までの…
Up until now, being afraid...
どんなに どんなに 手を取り合っていても
No matter how, no matter how much we hold hands,
最初から最後まで始まりはない
there is no beginning, from start to finish.
笑おう
Let's smile.
弱くない 弱くない 君は弱くないよ
You're not weak, you're not weak, you're not weak!
貰ってばかりの私じゃないから
Because I'm not just someone who only receives,
最初から最後まで何もなかったなんて言わせないよ絶対
Don't you dare say there was nothing from start to finish!
これが物語だったなら 君をこの勇気だけで簡単に救えるのに
If this were a story, I could easily save you with just this courage,
いつかは 追い付いて 振り向いて 止まって 何回も 何回も 名前呼んで
Someday, catching up, turning back, stopping, calling your name over and over,
自慢気にいいよ 傷ついて 今を見れなくて 夢の中閉じこもり 眠る
proudly saying it's fine, hurt and unable to see the present, locked inside a dream, sleeping,
私に向けて 信じあって 見えあって 笑おう
facing me, believing in each other, meeting, let's smile.
剥がせない 気持ち
Feelings that cannot be peeled off,
食べて 生まれた
born from consuming,
裏表の本音を すべて受け入れつつも
while accepting all true feelings, both inside and out,
どうして欲しくて 上げたくなくて いつだって いつだって 優しくなれない乗り越えて 向き合った 嘘つきな世界
wanting why... not wanting to give, always, always unable to be kind, overcoming and facing a lying world,
怖がってて 今までの後悔
being afraid of regrets up until now,
私と消えて 本当なんてなくて 笑おう
disappear with me, there's no such thing as truth, let's smile,
そっと
softly.
あやめ先輩！
Ayame-senpai!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
いえいえ、誘っていただいてありがとうございます。
No, no, thank you for inviting me.
なんか遅みたいだな。ねえ、呼んで、呼ばせていただきました。
It feels a bit late, but... yeah, I invited you.
いえいえ、ありがとうございます！おっ、桜が降ってますよ。
No, no, thank you! Oh, cherry blossoms are falling.
そうなんです。あやめ先輩のために用意しました。
That's right. I prepared this for Ayame-senpai.
わあ、やったー！すごい！綺麗でしょ？
Yay! Wow! Pretty, right?
桜取れないかな？
Can we pick the cherry blossoms?
取れないか～
Can't pick them, huh~
いや、そう、あやめ先輩とあの1月にあの、かなたんのね、別荘の時にあの初めてあの、お話させていただいて、その頃は友達になるわと思って、友達になったつもりでいたんですけど。
Well, yeah. Back in January, at Kanata's vacation home, I talked with Ayame-senpai for the first time, and I thought we'd become friends... or so I thought.
いや、つもりじゃないですよ！友達ですよ！
No, it's not just "thinking"! We are friends!
え、でも、半年前何かありましたっけ？
Eh, but, did something happen half a year ago?
いや、なんかね、ちょっと勘違いしてました、私。
Well, you see, I kind of misunderstood something.
え？いやいや、違う違う違う違う。
Eh? No, no, no, no, no.
違うんです、違うんです！違うんです！
It's different, it's different! It's different!
違うんです。あの、でも、そう、でもちょっとあやめ先輩とちょっと思い切ってあの、なんかしたいなと思ってで、一番やっぱり歌ってみたかったんですよね。
It's different. But I wanted to summon up the courage to do something with Ayame-senpai, and above all, I really wanted to sing together.
え、でもね、ようもね歌いたかったの、フレアちゃんの。
Eh, but, you know, I wanted to sing too, Flare-chan's—
え、本当ですか？めちゃうれし…めちゃうれし…えっ、合ってます？
Eh, really? So happy... so happy... Eh, is that right?
え、すごい、え、なんかね、よ、感動しちゃったの。
Eh, amazing, eh, like, I was so moved.
褒め上手！
You're good at praising!
いやいや、歌いながら、え？ちょっと、酔いたち、良くない？
No, no, while singing, eh? Wait, aren't we getting a bit emotional?
思ったし、私、あやめ先輩って、本間に可愛いのよって思って。
I thought so, and I thought, "Ayame-senpai is truly so cute."
ね、ちょっと褒め上手なんだけど。
You're too good at praising me.
なんかもうね、否定できることが何もない。本当に可愛くて。
There's nothing to deny. She's genuinely so cute.
なんか、今日写真、記念写真も撮っていいですか？
Um, can we take a commemorative photo today?
え、え、ぜひお願いします！
Eh, eh, please do!
え、ちょっと可愛く撮ってもらってもいいですか？おに、おに、おに、可愛い～！
Can you make it look cute? Oni, oni, oni, cute~!
に、いち、に、の、さん、に、いち、に、に、に……
Two, one, two, and three, two, one, two...
いやー、ありがとうございます！
Oh, thank you very much!
Thank you so much!
またあの、今度はあの、なんかゲームとか一緒に……
Also, next time let's play some games together...
ぜひお願いします！
Please!
やった、雑談にさせます！
Yay, let's chat!
やった、ずーっと待ってます！
Yay, I'll be waiting forever!
ありがとうございます、またぜひお願いします！
Thank you, please let's do it again!
はーい、ありがとねー！
Yay, thank you!
お疲れ様でしたー！
Good job!
え、で、次の展開、次の展開！
Eh, and the next development, the next development!
いつもの場所で
[Title: At This Usual Place]
いつか僕らが 未来 振り返る時には
Someday when we look back on the future,
いつもの場所で キミが笑って
you'll be smiling in this usual place.
残酷に過ぎ行く 時間の中で
Within the cruelly passing time,
探し求めていたもの
what we were searching for...
すれ違う世界に 閉じ込められた
trapped in a world where we pass each other by,
目に見えないヒカリ
an invisible light.
特別なほど 愛する者へ
To the one I love so specially,
打ち明けられずにいた
I couldn't bring myself to confess.
過ごした日々の 一つ一つが
Every single day we spent
戸惑いをピリオドに変える
turns our hesitation into a full stop.
いつか僕らが 未来 振り返る時には
Someday when we look back on the future,
いつもの場所で キミが笑って
you'll be smiling in this usual place.
重ね合われた みんなの想いが 世界線を創る
Everyone's overlapping feelings create the world line.
どんな雨にも 負けない信じ合える気持ち
A feeling of believing in each other that won't lose to any rain.
この空の観測者 この空は明日の証明
The observer of this sky, this sky is proof of tomorrow.
いつまでも変わらない 景色なんて 絶対叶わぬ夢
Scenery that never changes is a dream that will never come true.
奇跡のような出会い せめてあの日を 消したりしないで
A miraculous encounter—at least don't erase that day.
好きな気持ちが勇気に変わる 科学的じゃないけど
Feelings of love turn into courage—though it's not scientific.
戸惑いのない キミの言葉が
Your unambiguous words
本当の答えを導く
lead us to the true answer.
あの日僕らは 出会い 大切な何かを
On that day, we met and searched
いつものこの場所で 探していたね
for something important always at this place.
何気なく 過ぎゆく時間の その意味を知っている
I know the meaning of why time passes so casually.
たとえどんなに 二人 離れてしまっても
No matter how far apart we may be,
この空の観測者 この空は明日の証明
the observer of this sky, this sky is proof of tomorrow.
たとえ僕らは 遠く 離れてしまっても
Even if we are separated far apart,
いつものこの場所で 繋がっている
we are connected always at this place.
切なくてロマンチックだね まだ知らない明日
It's painful yet romantic, this unknown tomorrow.
いつか僕らが 未来 振り返る時には
Someday when we look back on the future,
いつもの場所で キミが笑って
you'll be smiling in this usual place.
イェーイ！
Yay!
ライビュ！
Live viewing!
いや、だから今もすごいもう、いついついつMC入るみたいな顔してたよ
You had this look like, "When is the MC starting?"
そうそう、そ、そ、そ、そって感じで、ちょっと焦っちゃった
Yeah, exactly, so I panicked a bit.
いや、まずお誕生日おめでとう！
First of all, happy birthday!
ありがとう！おめでとうって言われる前に
Thank you! Before you even said—
言われる前にありがとうって、気が早い、気が早い
You're way too eager! Way too eager!
いや、だからLamyとはさ、一緒に悪魔してじゃん
I mean, Lamy and I did that devil thing together...
なんだったけ、なんかちょっとダサいの見つけてよね、なんだっけ
What was it? We found something kind of uncool, right?
うん、ちょっと次の曲までの繋ぎしとこ
Yeah, let's fill the gap until the next song.
あの、あの時のやつでしょ、なんかダサすぎて忘れちゃった
That time's thing, right? It was so uncool I forgot.
でも今後それでやるんでしょ、雪降るロケやめたから
You're gonna do that from now on since we quit snow location shoots?
えー、今日は、あの、そんな二人で、下駄の曲をね、Lamyにめっちゃ愛そうと思って
Today, the two of us are gonna sing a geta song that Lamy loves so much...
ウィキペディアで見たって
I saw it on Wikipedia!
そう、本人に聞きなよ！なんでウィキなんだよ、自分で調べてこれお前のでやるってアピールしたかった
Go ask the person herself! Why Wikipedia? I wanted to appeal that I looked it up myself.
ありがとう！嬉しいよ！ほら、記念写真撮ろ、記念写真、せっかくだし
Thank you! I'm so happy! Let's take a commemorative photo since we're here!
イェーイ！そんなテンションなのこれ？気が合わなさすぎるんだけど
Yay! Is this really that kind of vibe? We're way too mismatched!
いや、ありがとう！また一緒に、また一緒にね！
Yeah, thank you! Let's do it together again!
ありがとうね！
Thank you!
泣き虫側隠れてるのはどちら様
Which of us is hiding behind tears?
笑われた分だけやり返せ
Fight back for every time you were laughed at!
今に見とろと 手に取り得た物は
Just wait and see, the things we got in hand...
爆弾やナイフなんて物じゃないけれど
aren't bombs or knives, even if they're not much.
一切合切今後どうなったって約束しよう
No matter what happens from now on, let's make a promise—
背中の値札を剥ぎ取れ
rip off the price tag on your back!
廃材みたいな 毎日だけど
Everyday feels like scraps of waste,
捨てるのは まだ早いだろ
but it's still too early to throw it all away.
今日も打ち震えながら 終点駅のホームで
Today too, trembling on the platform at the terminal station,
明日の僕がまだ待っている
tomorrow's me is still waiting.
わがままで横暴な主のお迎えを
Awaiting a selfish and tyrannical master...
どうせ何年経って車が空飛べど
Even if cars fly through the sky years from now,
きっと何年経って機械が喋れど
even if machines learn to speak years from now,
何だって言いたいんだ
what is it you really want to say?
便利って言う前に
Before you talk about convenience,
心の傷口を治してくれ
heal the wounds in my heart first.
あんな空でミサイルが飛ぶのなら
If missiles are flying in a sky like that,
そんなもので幸せを乞うのなら
and if you're begging for happiness through such things,
優しい人にならなくちゃ
I have to become a kind person.
僕は僕を肯定していけるかな
Can I learn to accept myself?
頭を上げて前向けと言われても
Even if they tell me to lift my head and look forward,
暗闇じゃ前もクソもないな
in the darkness there is no front or back.
一人で居れど 二人で居れど
Whether I'm by myself or with someone else,
孤独は孤独に変わりゃしねえ
loneliness never changes into anything else.
死にたいとか そんな歌を歌って
Singing songs about wanting to die,
またそれかと嘲笑打たれた
and getting mocked with "not that again"—
だけどそれ程のことしか
but that's the only kind of thing...
口からこぼれる言葉がどうしても見つからないよ
that spills from my mouth; I just can't find anything else.
今日も僕はまたこうして改札に吸い込まれる
Today too, I am sucked right into the ticket gate,
明日が
waiting for tomorrow...
泣きべそばっかかいてんのはどちら様
Who's the one who's always crying...
笑われた分だけやり返せ
Fight back as much as you've been laughed at!
今に見ろと手にした物は 爆弾やナイフなんて物じゃないけれど
What I took in my hand, saying "You'll see," isn't a bomb or a knife,
一切合算 今後どうなったって約束しよう 背中の値札を引っぺがせ
Let's promise whatever happens from now on, rip off the price tag on your back!
廃材みたいな毎日だけど 捨てるのはまだ早いだろ
Though every day is like scrap, it's still too early to throw it away.
今日も打ち震えながら終点駅のホームで 明日の僕がまだ待っている
Today too, trembling at the station platform, tomorrow's me is still waiting
わがままで横暴な主人の出迎えを
To welcome a selfish and tyrannical master.
どうせ何年経って車が空飛べど きっと何年経って機械が喋れども
Even if cars fly in a few years, surely even if machines talk in a few years,
何だって言いたいんだい 便利って言う前に
What is it you want to say? Before talking about convenience,
心の傷口を治してくれ
heal the wounds in my heart.
あんな空でミサイルが飛ぶのなら そんなもので幸せを乞うのなら 優しい人にならなくちゃ
If missiles are flying in that sky, if we're begging for happiness with such things, we have to become kind people.
僕は僕を肯定していけるかな
Can I continue to affirm who I am?
すずなんの曲は、
Suzu-nan's song is...
こっちは？
This one?
スリル、ショック、サスペンス...
Thrill, shock, suspense...
違うんです、この曲違うんです。ハウトゥー世界征服です。
No, that's wrong. This song is different. It's "How-To World Domination".
そうなんですよ。リハーサルってさ。
That's right. During rehearsal, you know...
リハでないっしょくめい二人で、あの、どんなに好きにしようかって考えてた結果、
The two of us desperately tried to figure out how much we wanted to do it during rehearsal,
もうどうしても、どうしても、チュリリリリ、チュリリリリ、チュチュチュチュチュチュ...
and no matter what, we just had to do chu-ri-ri-ri...
もう何をどうしてもこうするしかなくなってさ、もうじゃあこれでいこうって。
We had no choice but to pose like this no matter what, so we went with it.
あ、ふーたん、誕生日らしいね！
Ah, Fu-tan, it's your birthday, right!
そうなんだよ！おめでとう！
That's right! Congratulations!
ありがとう！直接会うのと忙しいのにね、ありがとう！
Thank you! Even though you're busy meeting in person, thank you!
いやそんな、だって二人で歌うって想像しないからね。
No way, because we never imagined singing together.
そう、てか初めて、なんか一緒にした、誰かと一緒に歌うみたいな、三人とかね。シラケンとかはあったんだけど。
Right, and it's my first time singing with someone else like this... We've had Shiraken and stuff.
なんか、すいちゃんと歌ってみたいなと思って、歌うんならでも、すいちゃんのかっこいい低音と、私得意だって、こーん、と合わさったら聞いてみたくて、あんましすいちゃんってさ、そういうの歌ってないなと思って。
I thought I'd love to sing with Suisei, and if we were going to sing, I wanted to hear how Suisei's cool low notes and my forte—high notes—blend together, because Suisei doesn't usually sing that kind of song.
いや、高いの無理！で、なんか合わさったの聞いたら、ちょっと、これもアリだって思って、めちゃ嬉しいなと思って、私もちょっと頑張ろうと思って。
No way, high notes are impossible! But when I heard us blended, I thought, "This is actually pretty good, I'm so happy," and decided to do my best too.
いや、ハウトゥー世界征服めちゃあってたと思う。いや本当、私もね、すいちゃんと歌ってめちゃ嬉しかったし、なんか、うるさいなお前なんてが、かっこよくて大嫌いだ！でも今年は好きだと思ったからさ。
I think "How-To World Domination" really fit us. I was so happy singing with Suisei, and lines like "You're so annoying" were so cool, and "I hate you! But I love you"—I thought it was great.
いや、頑張りました、あのコーン本当に。私、もうすーたんがスコーンって高音出すからさ、すいちゃんは頑張って、もう下のほうを支えました。
Yeah, I worked hard on those high notes. Su-tan hit those high notes so smoothly, so Suisei worked hard to support the lower part.
いやでも、そう支えてもらった低音がかっこよすぎて、めちゃ好きって思った。ありがとう！めちゃ楽しかった！
Yeah, but the low notes you supported were so cool, I loved them. Thank you! It was so much fun!
また一緒に歌いたい！ね、また一緒に歌いたい！
I want to sing together again! Right, let's sing together again!
どこへ行こうか 計画なしで 歌いながらキミノ向こうへ
Where shall we go? Without a plan, singing towards the other side of you,
迷ってるの？ボケしてるの？ それはみんな次第！
Are you lost? Are you spacing out? That depends on everyone!
まだまだ楽しい見たいみたい でもでも時間が足りない ワクワクすぐ明日へ 思い切って 張り切って 前向いてさ 進もう！
Still want to see and enjoy more, but time is running out, excitedly straight to tomorrow, with all my might, enthusiastic, looking forward, let's move on!
せーのっ！ でっかく起きて 遊び尽くしちゃえ やりすぎたぐらいで イッツ・オーライ！
Ready, set! Wake up big, play to your heart's content, even if you overdo it, it's all right!
早起きよりも 徹夜しちゃお なんとかしちゃうはずだから
Rather than waking up early, let's stay up all night, it'll somehow work out!
ピンチはチャンスになるからさ イッツ・オール・オッケー！
Because a pinch turns into a chance, it's all-okay!
みんなで笑えば無敵だね イッツ・オール・オッケー！
If everyone laughs together, we're invincible, it's all-okay!
なんたって戦略で 突き抜けちゃって 真っ直ぐな気持ちで行こう
No matter what, with strategy, breaking through, let's go with a straight feeling!
ホップステップジャンプで飛び出そう！
Let's hop, step, jump and leap out!
緊張に行くだけじゃ それはそれで退屈だね わがままかもしれないけど 失敗は成功の元！
Just going nervously—that in itself is boring, though it might be selfish, failure is the source of success!
とかかっこつけてみたけど やらかしちゃった日の夜は 枕に向かって叫んだ
I tried to sound cool like that, but on the night I messed up, I screamed into my pillow,
それもみんなが聞いてくれるから悪くないね！
Even so, everyone listens, so it's not bad!
どこへ行こうか 計画ナシで
Where should we go? With no plan in mind,
歌いながら気の向く方へ
singing as we head wherever we feel.
迷ってるの？ 冒険してるの？
Are we lost? Are we on an adventure?
それはみんな次第！
That's all up to everyone!
まだまだ楽しみ足んないっ
We still haven't had enough fun—
足んないっ
not enough fun—
でもでも時間が足んないっ
but we don't have enough time—
足んないっ
not enough time—
ワクワクする明日へ
towards an exciting tomorrow!
思い切って張り切って前向いて
Taking a bold step forward,
さあ 進もう！
come on, let's move forward!
せーのっ！
Ready, set!
いつだって本気で！
Always go all out!
遊び尽えしちゃえ！
Play to your heart's content!
やりすぎちゃうくらいで
Going a bit too far is just right—
イッツ・オーライ！
it's all right!
早起きよりも
Rather than waking up early,
徹夜しちゃおう
let's stay up all night!
なんとかなっちゃうはずだから！
Because somehow it'll all work out!
ピンチはチャンスになるからさ
Because a pinch becomes a chance—
イッツ・オール・オッケー！
it's all okay!
みんなで笑えば無敵だね
If everyone smiles, we're invincible—
イッツ・オール・オッケー！
it's all okay!
なんたって全力で！
No matter what, with all our might—
突き抜けちゃって！
break right through!
真っ直ぐな気持ちで行こう！
Let's go with a straight, honest feeling!
ホップ ステップ ジャンプで飛び出そう！
Hop, step, jump, and let's leap out!
順調に行くだけじゃ それはそれで退屈だね
Just going smoothly—that in itself is kind of boring, isn't it?
わがままかもしれないけど 失敗は成功の元！
Might be a bit selfish, but failure is the stepping stone to success!
とかカッコつけてみたけど やらかしちゃった夜は
I tried sounding cool like that, but on nights I mess up,
枕に向かって叫んだ
I scream into my pillow.
それもみんなが聞いてくれるから悪くないよね！
But since everyone listens, it's not so bad!
う〜っ、せーのっ！
Ready, set!
今しかできないことしようよ！
Let's do what we can only do right now!
心配ご無用 無問題！
No worries at all, no problem!
走る前からつまずくことを
Thinking about tripping before we even start
考えてちゃしょうがない
is just no good.
もしも雨が降ったとしたら
Just in case it rains,
とっておきの傘をさそうよ
let's open up our favorite umbrella!
なんたって全力で！ 突き抜けちゃって！
No matter what, with all our might! Break right through!
真っ直ぐな気持ちで行こう！
Let's go with a straight, honest feeling!
ホップ ステップ ジャンプで飛び出そう！
Hop, step, jump, and let's leap out!
なかなかお布団から出られない日もある
There are days when it's hard to get out of bed,
でも明日から そう明日から本気を出すんだ！
but starting tomorrow, yes, starting tomorrow, I'll get serious!
気分が済むまで！ 日が暮れるまで！
Until I'm satisfied! Until the sun goes down!
門限なんか無視で イッツ・オーライ！
Ignoring any curfew, it's all right!
早起きよりも徹夜しちゃおう
Rather than waking up early, let's stay up all night!
なんとかなっちゃうはずだから！
Because somehow it'll all work out!
ピンチはチャンスになるからさ イッツ・オール・オッケー！
Because a pinch becomes a chance—it's all okay!
みんなで笑えば無敵だね イッツ・オール・オッケー！
If everyone smiles, we're invincible—it's all okay!
なんたって全力で！ 突き抜けちゃって！
No matter what, with all our might! Break right through!
真っ直ぐな気持ちで行こう！
Let's go with a straight, honest feeling!
ホップ ステップ ジャンプで飛び出そう！
Hop, step, jump, and let's leap out!
なんたって全力で！ 突き抜けちゃって！
No matter what, with all our might! Break right through!
真っ直ぐな気持ちで行こう！
Let's go with a straight, honest feeling!
ホップ ステップ ジャンプで飛び出そう！
Hop, step, jump, and let's leap out!
今日は会いに来てくれてありがとう！不知火フレア誕生日記念グッズを紹介しちゃうよ。
Thanks for coming to see me today! I'll be introducing my birthday commemorative goods.
lackパパの超キュートな描き下ろしLEDアクリルスタンドライトや、君たちエルフレンドのぬいぐるみ！
There's an ultra-cute LED acrylic stand light drawn by lack-papa, and plushies of you Elfriends!
膝にのせてぎゅって抱きしめられちゃうほど良いサイズ。
They're a great size, perfect for holding on your lap and hugging tight.
帽子や時計を自分好みにアレンジしてね。そしておしゃれでシンプルで可愛いマルチポーチ！
Customize hats and watches however you like! And a stylish, simple, cute multi-pouch!
私とお揃いで一緒に持たない？次に誕生日を記念して作っちゃったよ、ブレスレット！
Won't you match with me and carry it together? Next, to commemorate my birthday, we made a bracelet!
君の推しは私だぞってアピールしてくれちゃうよね。
It'll really show off that your oshi is me, won't it?
そんでもってフルセットの購入特典！数量限定だけど今年も直筆サイン書いちゃうぞ。さらににお知らせです！私のLINEスタンプが発売されるってよ！
And on top of that, the full set purchase bonus! It's limited in quantity, but this time too I'll write a handwritten autograph. And furthermore, an announcement! My LINE stamps are going on sale!
イラストは佐々木先生が書いてくれたよ！使いやすいスタンプがいっぱいだよ。
The illustrations were drawn by Sasaki-sensei! There are lots of easy-to-use stamps.
恥ずかしいけど、いくつか私が描いたイラストもあるよ。これで終わったと思うな！最後に歌った私の新曲、
It's a bit embarrassing, but there are also a few illustrations drawn by me. Don't think it's over yet! Lastly, my new song that I sang,
「全力ジャンピング！」がこのあと0時からリリースされるよ！MVの公開はもう少しだけ待っててね。
"Zenryoku Jumping!", will be released tonight at midnight! Please wait just a little longer for the MV release.
朝くなっちゃったけど、今年も今年もたくさんみんなからおめでとうって言ってもらえて幸せだ！みんな、いつも本当にありがとう。愛してるぞ！
Morning has come, but I'm so happy to receive "congratulations" from everyone again this year! Everyone, thank you all so much as always. I love you!